<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chicago Real Estate Blog - eXp Realty</title>
    <description>Our mission at The Spaniak Team is to be your best resource for Chicago real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The The Spaniak Team, your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 12:09:09 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 12:09:09 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: Why Should You Sell Now?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gBETpOX-lrw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re still trying to recover from the pandemic, and protests are happening all over the country. It seems like the world is in chaos. However, there are a few reasons why now is a great time to list your home for sale. Buyers are out looking for houses right now; they’re ready and anxious to move. Many sellers aren’t listing yet because they don’t want people walking through their homes amid the coronavirus, which means huge opportunities for those who do put their houses on the market now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also wrote an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://patch.com/illinois/northbrook/lack-home-inventory-north-shore-it-true?&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;article for Patch.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on why now might be the best time to list your home for the most money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’m happy to help!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Virtual Tour:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://my.matterport.com/show/?m=VzXLmZPg3ae&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/uploads/2-.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 15:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-why-should-you-sell-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-why-should-you-sell-now.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Higher Orbits' Go For Launch Event</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KJoiGP2n3XQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have a child grades 9-12 who is interested in STEM? If so, see below… or please share this post in any other groups you think might be interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am giving away one scholarship🎖to a deserving student 9-12th grade to attend &lt;a href=&quot;https://higherorbits.org/go-for-launch/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Higher Orbits’ Go For Launch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; two-day event in Spring Grove, Illinois on July 13 &amp;amp; 14.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an incredible not-for-profit that gives kids the chance to send an experiment to the International Space Station. I love 🤩 Higher Orbits and its mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSerg9-5k_ULVgS7fJQm7fTBRdgI9wgw7oGvFBFOknw3EYq5Xw/viewform&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to fill out the form and for more information!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 14:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/higher-orbits-go-for-launch-event.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/higher-orbits-go-for-launch-event.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Future of the Real Estate Industry</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7Eg4ZE5KXWk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With COVID-19 affecting nearly every industry in this country, what will the future of real estate look like? I wanted to share my thoughts today after having observed many changes over the last month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s an outline of my discussion, with timestamps so that you can skip around to the section(s) that interest you most:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:15- A story about a buyer who I worked with virtually&lt;br /&gt;2:00- A message to everyone who was planning to move in the next year&lt;br /&gt;3:15- Why homebuyers should be looking on the MLS and the private network&lt;br /&gt;4:00- Advice for owners of luxury homes and starter homes&lt;br /&gt;5:00- Some of the new technology we’re implementing to further assist buyers and sellers&lt;br /&gt;6:00- How we’re beefing up virtual showings to attract more buyers&lt;br /&gt;7:05- How to use your time at home to your advantage for a future move&lt;br /&gt;8:05- A few different ways I can help you during this time &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jaIgwyffdKo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to check out one of our fly-through tours.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://calendly.com/katispaniak&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Schedule an appointment with Kati&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Free webinar with Kati:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Times &amp;amp; New Methods for Selling Your Home&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Create a game plan to get your house sold now or in the future for the most amount of money in the least amount of time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, May 6th 2020&lt;/strong&gt;, at 4:00 PM&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday, May 9th 2020&lt;/strong&gt;, at 10:00 AM&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, May 14th 2020&lt;/strong&gt;, at 10:00 AM&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://event.webinarjam.com/register/5/7vnvquy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;→ Register Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me at all, I’m here to answer them. There’s no cost and no obligation, I just truly want to advise you on the best route of action possible. Just give me a call or send me an email today. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 16:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-future-of-the-real-estate-industry.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-future-of-the-real-estate-industry.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Which Houses Sell Fast in Our Current Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_MqFmmk8NRQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been talking about the importance of pricing for years. The market has changed a little bit, though, and buyers aren’t as concerned about price as they are about condition. &lt;strong&gt;Even if you’re priced correctly for your home’s condition, it’s a tough sale if there’s a lot of work that needs to be done.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When buyers go online, they won’t like homes that don’t look ready to go. They won’t see the house in person if there isn’t some emotional connection. If they do walk into your house and it has a lot of obvious deferred maintenance, it’s going to be a tough sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Homes that aren’t in good condition may not sell at all.%20http://localhost:4000/which-houses-sell-fast-in-our-current-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Homes that aren’t in good condition may not sell at all.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re maybe a year or two out from selling, it’s time for you to take care of that deferred maintenance now.&lt;/strong&gt; Your roof, windows, HVAC system, etc., should all be checked and in proper working order. Your house needs to be in good condition to sell in this market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A buyer I worked with recently found a home that was on the market and in great condition. They loved that the roof was new, the mechanicals were in good working order, and the kitchen was fresh and updated with appliances. &lt;strong&gt;Everything in the house had been taken care of, so it was an easy sell.&lt;/strong&gt; There was nothing left in the house that needed to be “taken care of.” The only thing that the buyers needed to do was customize it to their liking. This home sold over list price, as will most homes that are in good condition right now.  Homes that aren’t in good condition may not sell at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about the updates and upgrades you should make before you sell, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 13:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/which-houses-sell-fast-in-our-current-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/which-houses-sell-fast-in-our-current-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Market Update &amp; an Ugly Tax Reality</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3I245u4vW1A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of hammering you with stats, today I’ll offer a market update for the North Shore of Chicago based on my boots-on-the-ground experience. Generally speaking, it still holds that if a house is in good condition and priced correctly, it will definitely sell. But what’s the mood? What am I hearing day in and day out? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxes are a really big issue right now. Buyers nowadays are much smarter than they used to be it seems; they’re very aware that property taxes will continue to skyrocket here in Illinois. When they’re looking at houses, they’re factoring in taxes first. &lt;strong&gt;A lot of high-tax houses are sitting, and will likely continue to sit. Sellers, there’s not much you can do about this, other than cut your price. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, it’s ridiculous that elected officials in our state can’t grasp the gravity of the situation unfolding. Let me make this clear: This isn’t intended to be a political commentary to sway Illinois voters one way or another; I’m just stating that if you keep raising property taxes in a state, people will eventually start leaving in droves, which, in turn, will decrease home values. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a buyer recently find a home to their liking way outside of the city for $250,000. The problem, however, was that the taxes on this property were $13,000. This blew their whole budget, and they had to pass on the home. Sadly, I just feel like the issue of exorbitant property taxes isn’t being addressed by our representatives. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Buyers in our market are availing themselves of all of the data available online these days.%20http://localhost:4000/a-market-update-an-ugly-tax-reality.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Buyers in our market are availing themselves of all of the data available online these days.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You must appeal your taxes every year.&lt;/strong&gt; If you need help with this, just let me know, as I can connect you with a trusted professional. If you know you’ll be selling and your taxes are high, you may want to give yourself a longer listing time to account for the fact that not as many buyers will be able to afford that aspect of your home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buyers in our market are availing themselves of all of the data available online these days, and, on average, are waiting a little longer to buy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My overall feel of the North Shore market: &lt;strong&gt;Things are selling but you have to make the necessary upgrades and do things right—cross your t’s and dot your i’s&lt;/strong&gt;. Again, with regard to the tax situation, it’s just painful for everyone. I’ve included some links to more of the statistical breakdown of the North Shore housing market below. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have additional questions about this or any other real estate topic, feel free to give me a call or send an email. I’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;North Shore Statistics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWo-6TD&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWo-6TD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Median Sales Price&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWB-jt6&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWB-jt6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Average Sales Price&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAW2-MAx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAW2-MAx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Homes for Sale&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWZ-Vvo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWZ-Vvo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;New Listings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWY-zVB&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWY-zVB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Average Market Time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWO-LDy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWO-LDy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Under Contract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWX-yKL&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWX-yKL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Closed Sales&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWi-M2N&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWi-M2N&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Median Price Per Square Foot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWD-pdn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWD-pdn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Average Price Per Square Foot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWW-eAP&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWW-eAP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Months Supply&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 13:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-market-update-an-ugly-tax-reality.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-market-update-an-ugly-tax-reality.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Deals Fall Through</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nSeU5lJ3M70?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re examining why deals fall through in our current market. It’s so painful having to go from contract to contract in attorney review; this period of time is when most difficulties arise, so we’ll start off our message explaining exactly what attorney review is and how best to handle it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to skip to topics that interest you most: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0:58 — Keep your attorney review period as short as possible &lt;br /&gt;2:12 — Buyers backing out after making an offer, or requesting too much for a credit &lt;br /&gt;3:25 — Buyers and sellers getting emotional and losing perspective of the transaction &lt;br /&gt;4:00 — How a contingent offer can give buyers an upper hand&lt;br /&gt;5:13 — Advice to sellers going into attorney review/advice to buyers for requesting credits&lt;br /&gt;6:24 — Wrapping things up &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have further questions about this or any other real estate topic, please feel free to call, email, or explore our website. We’re always having seminars on how to sell your home (check the email that led you here for a link to more information on the next one). These events are very casual—no pressure at all, just come with questions and we’ll be happy to help you. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 13:55:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-deals-fall-through.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-deals-fall-through.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Most Important Thing to Do Before Selling?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TWnCFOg7GJI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m answering the question, “What is the most important thing to do to your home before listing it for sale?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You may be surprised, but the answer is to paint.&lt;/strong&gt; Why is painting so important? It’s fresh, makes the home smell like it’s been updated, and can hide a lot of imperfections. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I actually recommend painting over any other upgrade in terms of return on investment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You will need the right color to appeal to the most buyers possible.%20http://localhost:4000/whats-the-most-important-thing-to-do-before-selling.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You will need the right color to appeal to the most buyers possible.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will need the right color to appeal to the most buyers possible. Unless you’re an interior decorator, I’d reach out to someone like myself for advice on paint color. We know what’s going on in the market and we know what colors the buyers want to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you have wooden doors, they need to be painted also. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about painting or other things you can do to get your home ready for sale, feel free to reach out via phone or email. &lt;strong&gt;We’d also love to see you at our next seminar on February 25 in Downtown Northbrook.&lt;/strong&gt; You can &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/downsizing-where-do-you-start-tickets-92269976985&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;register here for free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and learn everything you need to know about selling a home, whether you’re ready to or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 13:51:09 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-the-most-important-thing-to-do-before-selling.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/whats-the-most-important-thing-to-do-before-selling.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Downsizing the Right Way</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/E-6hZ6d122s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re over the age of 50, you’ll probably want to start thinking about downsizing. Perhaps your kids are grown up and off to college, and it’s time to think about the next stage in your life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downsizing is a topic I discuss with people all the time, and &lt;strong&gt;the first thing you need to know is where you’ll go.&lt;/strong&gt; I’d say that three out of every five sellers I currently work with are moving out of state or renting, and one of the reasons why is they can’t find the housing they’re looking for. There aren’t a lot of great downsizing options on the North Shore. This is why you have to start looking for homes early and know what you’re looking for. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, there aren’t a lot of large ranches in maintenance-free communities because they take up a lot of space. If you do find one of these properties in a maintenance-free community, it will be very expensive. When it comes to downsizing, something usually has to give in terms of what you want in a home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Millennials want homes to look move-in ready.%20http://localhost:4000/downsizing-the-right-way.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Millennials want homes to look move-in ready.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, &lt;strong&gt;think about how you’ll sell your home.&lt;/strong&gt; Millennial buyers are different than the buyers that were around when I bought my home. They look at things differently, and their priorities are not your priorities. You have to consider the fact that you’ll have to target your house to a whole new market and understand that demographic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By and large, millennials want homes to look move-in ready. They’re not willing to take on many projects; they’d rather have everything updated. This is why, no matter what your downsizing timeline is, you need to talk to an agent sooner rather than later so that you understand your new target market. Where should you spend your money (and where shouldn’t you)? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re serious about downsizing the right way, &lt;strong&gt;I’m hosting a seminar that will cover this topic in-depth on January 29 at my office.&lt;/strong&gt; Sellers who’ve attended my previous seminars found it very informative because I offer all of my insight, whether you hire me as your agent or not. At this seminar, I’ll go over the downsizing process step by step, so if you’re, say, five years away from actually downsizing, I highly recommend attending. Space is limited, so &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/downsizing-where-do-you-start-tickets-83655904061&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;use this link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to register now and find out the rest of the details.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can’t make it but you have more questions about this topic, feel free to call or email me. I’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 10:58:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/downsizing-the-right-way.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/downsizing-the-right-way.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Impact of a Teardown Tax on Property Values</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/g1U1AQ__6fg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s topic is affordable housing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bring this up because there is a new development opportunity that is likely coming to Northbrook in the near future: The Green Acres Country Club, a 127-acre parcel right off Dundee Road. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re already beginning the review process with the village board. Whenever there is a new housing development brought before the board, it starts a conversation about housing affordability and how we need to create an affordable housing fund and initiatives for people who are potential employees in Northbrook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One portion of the affordable housing initiative is the teardown tax, which could have a different result than perhaps the board intends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel free to follow along in the video above, or else you can use the timestamps I’ve provided below to navigate the conversation at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:13—The teardown tax &lt;br /&gt;3:31—The importance of communication when it comes to the subject of housing affordability&lt;br /&gt;5:10—How the teardown tax might actually hurt residents in Northbrook&lt;br /&gt;6:20—Balancing the concerns about affordable housing with concerns about the area residents&lt;br /&gt;7:31—Starting an important conversation in support of our residents&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a complex issue with many facets, but if you have any questions about the teardown tax and preserving the property values here in Northbrook, I’m free to talk. All you have to do is reach out to me anytime and we can discuss it in more detail. I’d be happy to have a conversation with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 16:00:45 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-impact-of-a-teardown-tax-on-property-values.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-impact-of-a-teardown-tax-on-property-values.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Should You Not Hire Me?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UP4n-HYwbAY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I am going to answer the question, “Why should you not hire me as your real estate agent?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truly, it’s if you don’t want the genuine truth. I am honest with my clients. &lt;strong&gt;I’m pretty blunt and frank.&lt;/strong&gt; I’m going to present it to you the way that I see it. I try to make it a bit softer, but I don’t want my clients to be in a position where a year or two after they’ve listed their house, they’re still on the market. I will be 100% honest with you even if you don’t like the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a real-life example. I was in a situation about a year and a half ago where I went to give a price estimate and the homeowners were interviewing three agents. I gave them a price of $649,000, but if they needed to sell immediately, I said $599,000. I was not chosen, they went with the agent that priced it at $769,000, which was way too high for the market. However, the other agent said, “Yeah, we’ll do it, we can get that.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, after six months that listing expired and they thought it was the agent’s fault when it wasn’t. Then they went with an agent that reduced it to $699,000. After that, it had to be reduced to $639,000, then $629,000, and finally, they decreased to $599,000, the price I had given them, 14 months later. Now, they still have not closed after 16 months on the market. So, they had carrying costs, time aggravation, and showing irritations. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I will be 100% honest with you even if you don’t like the answer.%20http://localhost:4000/why-should-you-not-hire-me.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I will be 100% honest with you even if you don’t like the answer.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Showing your house can be an agonizing experience&lt;/strong&gt; and having showings and being ready for showings every day is arduous. Imagine being on the market for 16 months! Maybe they simply didn’t like me, but the point is that they didn’t listen to what I was saying as being valid. It’s fine to do that, but it ended up costing them time and money. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work with an agent who you can trust and who knows the market. I do not want people to overspend on improvements on their home. I want people to sell their houses and sell quickly. To that end, our clients can cancel their listing agreement with us at any time because if they feel we are not being forthright, we want them to feel that they can leave. This allows us to have an improved conversation with our clients about the market. We’re telling you the truth about what will get your house sold. It’s up to you now to decide where you want to go with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, want to chat, or you want an estimate on your home with no obligation, feel free to reach out. The easiest way is to email me but I’m also available by phone or text as well. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 16:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-should-you-not-hire-me.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-should-you-not-hire-me.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
