<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Chicago Real Estate Podcast with Kati Spaniak</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Spaniak Team - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Kati Spaniak</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2020-06-09 12:09:09 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Kati Spaniak</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Info@SpaniakTeam.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Kati Spaniak</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Chicago Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Spaniak Team - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: Why Should You Sell Now?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-why-should-you-sell-now.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2020-06-08 15:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/June/Q-+Why+Should+You+Sell+Now_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re still trying to recover from the pandemic, and protests are happening all over the country. It seems like the world is in chaos. However, there are a few reasons why now is a great time to list your home for sale. Buyers are out looking for houses right now; they’re ready and anxious to move. Many sellers aren’t listing yet because they don’t want people walking through their homes amid the coronavirus, which means huge opportunities for those who do put their houses on the market now.

We also wrote an article for Patch.com on why now might be the best time to list your home for the most money.

If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’m happy to help!

New Virtual Tour:


</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/June/Q-+Why+Should+You+Sell+Now_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/June/Q-+Why+Should+You+Sell+Now_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Despite the negativity in the world, it’s still a great time to sell.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Despite the negativity in the world, it’s still a great time to sell.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Higher Orbits' Go For Launch Event</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/higher-orbits-go-for-launch-event.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2020-05-07 14:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Do you have a child grades 9-12 who is interested in STEM? If so, see below… or please share this post in any other groups you think might be interested.

I am giving away one scholarship🎖to a deserving student 9-12th grade to attend Higher Orbits’ Go For Launch two-day event in Spring Grove, Illinois on July 13 &amp; 14.

This is an incredible not-for-profit that gives kids the chance to send an experiment to the International Space Station. I love 🤩 Higher Orbits and its mission.

Click here to fill out the form and for more information!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I am giving away one scholarship to a deserving student!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I am giving away one scholarship to a deserving student!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Future of the Real Estate Industry</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-future-of-the-real-estate-industry.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-23 16:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/April/The+Future+of+the+Real+Estate+Industry.mp4</guid>
        <description>

With COVID-19 affecting nearly every industry in this country, what will the future of real estate look like? I wanted to share my thoughts today after having observed many changes over the last month.

Here’s an outline of my discussion, with timestamps so that you can skip around to the section(s) that interest you most:

1:15- A story about a buyer who I worked with virtually2:00- A message to everyone who was planning to move in the next year3:15- Why homebuyers should be looking on the MLS and the private network4:00- Advice for owners of luxury homes and starter homes5:00- Some of the new technology we’re implementing to further assist buyers and sellers6:00- How we’re beefing up virtual showings to attract more buyers7:05- How to use your time at home to your advantage for a future move8:05- A few different ways I can help you during this time 

Click here to check out one of our fly-through tours.

Schedule an appointment with KatiFree webinar with Kati:New Times &amp; New Methods for Selling Your HomeCreate a game plan to get your house sold now or in the future for the most amount of money in the least amount of time.Wednesday, May 6th 2020, at 4:00 PMSaturday, May 9th 2020, at 10:00 AMThursday, May 14th 2020, at 10:00 AM→ Register Here

If you have any questions for me at all, I’m here to answer them. There’s no cost and no obligation, I just truly want to advise you on the best route of action possible. Just give me a call or send me an email today. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/April/The+Future+of+the+Real+Estate+Industry.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/April/The+Future+of+the+Real+Estate+Industry.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The real estate industry is much different now than it was just a few months ago. What does that mean for its future?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The real estate industry is much different now than it was just a few months ago. What does that mean for its future?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Which Houses Sell Fast in Our Current Market?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/which-houses-sell-fast-in-our-current-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-03 13:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/April/Which+Houses+Sell+Fast+in+Our+Current+Market_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’ve been talking about the importance of pricing for years. The market has changed a little bit, though, and buyers aren’t as concerned about price as they are about condition. Even if you’re priced correctly for your home’s condition, it’s a tough sale if there’s a lot of work that needs to be done.

When buyers go online, they won’t like homes that don’t look ready to go. They won’t see the house in person if there isn’t some emotional connection. If they do walk into your house and it has a lot of obvious deferred maintenance, it’s going to be a tough sell.

“Homes that aren’t in good condition may not sell at all.”

If you’re maybe a year or two out from selling, it’s time for you to take care of that deferred maintenance now. Your roof, windows, HVAC system, etc., should all be checked and in proper working order. Your house needs to be in good condition to sell in this market.

A buyer I worked with recently found a home that was on the market and in great condition. They loved that the roof was new, the mechanicals were in good working order, and the kitchen was fresh and updated with appliances. Everything in the house had been taken care of, so it was an easy sell. There was nothing left in the house that needed to be “taken care of.” The only thing that the buyers needed to do was customize it to their liking. This home sold over list price, as will most homes that are in good condition right now.  Homes that aren’t in good condition may not sell at all.

If you have any questions for me about the updates and upgrades you should make before you sell, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/April/Which+Houses+Sell+Fast+in+Our+Current+Market_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/April/Which+Houses+Sell+Fast+in+Our+Current+Market_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Your home’s condition is of the utmost importance in today’s market. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Your home’s condition is of the utmost importance in today’s market. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Market Update & an Ugly Tax Reality</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-market-update-an-ugly-tax-reality.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2020-03-16 13:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/March/A+Market+Update+%26+an+Ugly+Tax+Reality.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Instead of hammering you with stats, today I’ll offer a market update for the North Shore of Chicago based on my boots-on-the-ground experience. Generally speaking, it still holds that if a house is in good condition and priced correctly, it will definitely sell. But what’s the mood? What am I hearing day in and day out? 

Taxes are a really big issue right now. Buyers nowadays are much smarter than they used to be it seems; they’re very aware that property taxes will continue to skyrocket here in Illinois. When they’re looking at houses, they’re factoring in taxes first. A lot of high-tax houses are sitting, and will likely continue to sit. Sellers, there’s not much you can do about this, other than cut your price. 

In my opinion, it’s ridiculous that elected officials in our state can’t grasp the gravity of the situation unfolding. Let me make this clear: This isn’t intended to be a political commentary to sway Illinois voters one way or another; I’m just stating that if you keep raising property taxes in a state, people will eventually start leaving in droves, which, in turn, will decrease home values. 

I had a buyer recently find a home to their liking way outside of the city for $250,000. The problem, however, was that the taxes on this property were $13,000. This blew their whole budget, and they had to pass on the home. Sadly, I just feel like the issue of exorbitant property taxes isn’t being addressed by our representatives. 

“Buyers in our market are availing themselves of all of the data available online these days.”

You must appeal your taxes every year. If you need help with this, just let me know, as I can connect you with a trusted professional. If you know you’ll be selling and your taxes are high, you may want to give yourself a longer listing time to account for the fact that not as many buyers will be able to afford that aspect of your home. 

Buyers in our market are availing themselves of all of the data available online these days, and, on average, are waiting a little longer to buy. 

My overall feel of the North Shore market: Things are selling but you have to make the necessary upgrades and do things right—cross your t’s and dot your i’s. Again, with regard to the tax situation, it’s just painful for everyone. I’ve included some links to more of the statistical breakdown of the North Shore housing market below. 

As always, if you have additional questions about this or any other real estate topic, feel free to give me a call or send an email. I’d love to hear from you.

North Shore Statistics:

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWo-6TDMedian Sales Price

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWB-jt6Average Sales Price

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAW2-MAxHomes for Sale

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWZ-VvoNew Listings

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWY-zVBAverage Market Time

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWO-LDyUnder Contract

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWX-yKLClosed Sales

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWi-M2NMedian Price Per Square Foot

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWD-pdnAverage Price Per Square Foot

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/SAWW-eAPMonths Supply
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/March/A+Market+Update+%26+an+Ugly+Tax+Reality.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/March/A+Market+Update+%26+an+Ugly+Tax+Reality.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s what the North Shore market looks like from the perspective of someone who’s in the real estate trenches every day.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s what the North Shore market looks like from the perspective of someone who’s in the real estate trenches every day.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Deals Fall Through</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-deals-fall-through.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2020-02-28 13:55:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/February/Why+Deals+Fall+Through.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today we’re examining why deals fall through in our current market. It’s so painful having to go from contract to contract in attorney review; this period of time is when most difficulties arise, so we’ll start off our message explaining exactly what attorney review is and how best to handle it. 

Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to skip to topics that interest you most: 

0:58 — Keep your attorney review period as short as possible 2:12 — Buyers backing out after making an offer, or requesting too much for a credit 3:25 — Buyers and sellers getting emotional and losing perspective of the transaction 4:00 — How a contingent offer can give buyers an upper hand5:13 — Advice to sellers going into attorney review/advice to buyers for requesting credits6:24 — Wrapping things up 

If you have further questions about this or any other real estate topic, please feel free to call, email, or explore our website. We’re always having seminars on how to sell your home (check the email that led you here for a link to more information on the next one). These events are very casual—no pressure at all, just come with questions and we’ll be happy to help you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/February/Why+Deals+Fall+Through.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/February/Why+Deals+Fall+Through.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s what buyers and sellers should both know about why deals fall through, and how an experienced agent can help navigate the emotions of a transaction.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s what buyers and sellers should both know about why deals fall through, and how an experienced agent can help navigate the emotions of a transaction.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Most Important Thing to Do Before Selling?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-the-most-important-thing-to-do-before-selling.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2020-02-11 13:51:09 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/February/Whats+the+Most+Important+Thing+to+Do+Before+Selling_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m answering the question, “What is the most important thing to do to your home before listing it for sale?”

You may be surprised, but the answer is to paint. Why is painting so important? It’s fresh, makes the home smell like it’s been updated, and can hide a lot of imperfections. 

I actually recommend painting over any other upgrade in terms of return on investment.

“You will need the right color to appeal to the most buyers possible.”

You will need the right color to appeal to the most buyers possible. Unless you’re an interior decorator, I’d reach out to someone like myself for advice on paint color. We know what’s going on in the market and we know what colors the buyers want to see.

If you have wooden doors, they need to be painted also. 

If you have any questions for me about painting or other things you can do to get your home ready for sale, feel free to reach out via phone or email. We’d also love to see you at our next seminar on February 25 in Downtown Northbrook. You can register here for free, and learn everything you need to know about selling a home, whether you’re ready to or not.

We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/February/Whats+the+Most+Important+Thing+to+Do+Before+Selling_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/February/Whats+the+Most+Important+Thing+to+Do+Before+Selling_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you need to get your home ready for sale, there’s one thing you must do to increase its value: Paint.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you need to get your home ready for sale, there’s one thing you must do to increase its value: Paint.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Downsizing the Right Way</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/downsizing-the-right-way.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2020-01-21 10:58:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/January/Downsizing+the+Right+Way.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re over the age of 50, you’ll probably want to start thinking about downsizing. Perhaps your kids are grown up and off to college, and it’s time to think about the next stage in your life. 

Downsizing is a topic I discuss with people all the time, and the first thing you need to know is where you’ll go. I’d say that three out of every five sellers I currently work with are moving out of state or renting, and one of the reasons why is they can’t find the housing they’re looking for. There aren’t a lot of great downsizing options on the North Shore. This is why you have to start looking for homes early and know what you’re looking for. 

For example, there aren’t a lot of large ranches in maintenance-free communities because they take up a lot of space. If you do find one of these properties in a maintenance-free community, it will be very expensive. When it comes to downsizing, something usually has to give in terms of what you want in a home. 

“Millennials want homes to look move-in ready.”

Next, think about how you’ll sell your home. Millennial buyers are different than the buyers that were around when I bought my home. They look at things differently, and their priorities are not your priorities. You have to consider the fact that you’ll have to target your house to a whole new market and understand that demographic. 

By and large, millennials want homes to look move-in ready. They’re not willing to take on many projects; they’d rather have everything updated. This is why, no matter what your downsizing timeline is, you need to talk to an agent sooner rather than later so that you understand your new target market. Where should you spend your money (and where shouldn’t you)? 

If you’re serious about downsizing the right way, I’m hosting a seminar that will cover this topic in-depth on January 29 at my office. Sellers who’ve attended my previous seminars found it very informative because I offer all of my insight, whether you hire me as your agent or not. At this seminar, I’ll go over the downsizing process step by step, so if you’re, say, five years away from actually downsizing, I highly recommend attending. Space is limited, so use this link to register now and find out the rest of the details.  

If you can’t make it but you have more questions about this topic, feel free to call or email me. I’d love to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/January/Downsizing+the+Right+Way.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2020/January/Downsizing+the+Right+Way.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re thinking of downsizing in the near future, here are a few factors to think about.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re thinking of downsizing in the near future, here are a few factors to think about.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Impact of a Teardown Tax on Property Values</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-impact-of-a-teardown-tax-on-property-values.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-12-10 16:00:45 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/December/The+Impact+of+a+Teardown+Tax+on+Property+Values.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today’s topic is affordable housing.

I bring this up because there is a new development opportunity that is likely coming to Northbrook in the near future: The Green Acres Country Club, a 127-acre parcel right off Dundee Road. 

They’re already beginning the review process with the village board. Whenever there is a new housing development brought before the board, it starts a conversation about housing affordability and how we need to create an affordable housing fund and initiatives for people who are potential employees in Northbrook.

One portion of the affordable housing initiative is the teardown tax, which could have a different result than perhaps the board intends.

Feel free to follow along in the video above, or else you can use the timestamps I’ve provided below to navigate the conversation at your leisure:

1:13—The teardown tax 3:31—The importance of communication when it comes to the subject of housing affordability5:10—How the teardown tax might actually hurt residents in Northbrook6:20—Balancing the concerns about affordable housing with concerns about the area residents7:31—Starting an important conversation in support of our residents

This is a complex issue with many facets, but if you have any questions about the teardown tax and preserving the property values here in Northbrook, I’m free to talk. All you have to do is reach out to me anytime and we can discuss it in more detail. I’d be happy to have a conversation with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/December/The+Impact+of+a+Teardown+Tax+on+Property+Values.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/December/The+Impact+of+a+Teardown+Tax+on+Property+Values.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In light of a new housing development here in Northbrook, housing affordability has become the topic of the day. But is a teardown tax going to work out in favor of our residents?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In light of a new housing development here in Northbrook, housing affordability has become the topic of the day. But is a teardown tax going to work out in favor of our residents?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Should You Not Hire Me?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-should-you-not-hire-me.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-11-12 16:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/November/Why+Should+You+Not+Hire+Me_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I am going to answer the question, “Why should you not hire me as your real estate agent?”

Truly, it’s if you don’t want the genuine truth. I am honest with my clients. I’m pretty blunt and frank. I’m going to present it to you the way that I see it. I try to make it a bit softer, but I don’t want my clients to be in a position where a year or two after they’ve listed their house, they’re still on the market. I will be 100% honest with you even if you don’t like the answer.

Here is a real-life example. I was in a situation about a year and a half ago where I went to give a price estimate and the homeowners were interviewing three agents. I gave them a price of $649,000, but if they needed to sell immediately, I said $599,000. I was not chosen, they went with the agent that priced it at $769,000, which was way too high for the market. However, the other agent said, “Yeah, we’ll do it, we can get that.” 

Then, after six months that listing expired and they thought it was the agent’s fault when it wasn’t. Then they went with an agent that reduced it to $699,000. After that, it had to be reduced to $639,000, then $629,000, and finally, they decreased to $599,000, the price I had given them, 14 months later. Now, they still have not closed after 16 months on the market. So, they had carrying costs, time aggravation, and showing irritations. 

“I will be 100% honest with you even if you don’t like the answer.”

Showing your house can be an agonizing experience and having showings and being ready for showings every day is arduous. Imagine being on the market for 16 months! Maybe they simply didn’t like me, but the point is that they didn’t listen to what I was saying as being valid. It’s fine to do that, but it ended up costing them time and money. 

Work with an agent who you can trust and who knows the market. I do not want people to overspend on improvements on their home. I want people to sell their houses and sell quickly. To that end, our clients can cancel their listing agreement with us at any time because if they feel we are not being forthright, we want them to feel that they can leave. This allows us to have an improved conversation with our clients about the market. We’re telling you the truth about what will get your house sold. It’s up to you now to decide where you want to go with that.

If you have any questions, want to chat, or you want an estimate on your home with no obligation, feel free to reach out. The easiest way is to email me but I’m also available by phone or text as well. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/November/Why+Should+You+Not+Hire+Me_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/November/Why+Should+You+Not+Hire+Me_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m sharing the one true reason why you may not want to hire me as your real estate agent.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m sharing the one true reason why you may not want to hire me as your real estate agent.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>You’re Invited to My Upcoming Home Seller Seminar</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/youre-invited-to-my-upcoming-home-seller-seminar.html</link>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-10-27 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/October/Youre+Invited+to+My+Upcoming+Home+Seller+Seminar.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re thinking of selling your house, you probably have questions about what you can do to prepare it for the market. Well, you’re in luck, because we’re hosting a fantastic seller seminar soon, and you’re invited!

Join us on November 16 in downtown Northbrook at 9:30 a.m. to learn the answers to the following questions and more:


  When is the best time to list your house?
  What do you need to do to get your house ready to sell?
  What projects should you invest your money in?
  How do you buy and sell a home at the same time?
  If you can’t hold two houses at once, what can you do?
  What is a bridge loan?
  How can you get a mortgage if you’ve already retired and don’t have any income?
  How do you sell your house as a FSBO?
  How do you find and engage with a real estate attorney?
  Should you get a home inspection before you put your home on the market?
  How do you find the right real estate agent?


I promise this seminar will be incredibly informational to home sellers. Last year, one couple who attended ended up listing their home with me in the spring—they sold their house before it even went on the MLS! Doug and Nancy gave me a fantastic testimonial, which you can look at here.

“My wife and I were very impressed with Kati Spaniak and her team (about 5-7 people) at every step of the process.  They were great to work with and we always felt informed and confident they were going to deliver the best result.  You will be impressed by Kati’s knowledge of the local market.

Here is a little about our experience.  Kati does not try to ‘sweet talk’ you to get your listing.  Her feedback will be very well grounded and spot on.  When we first invited her to the house she walked through and gave us very honest feedback on condition, marketability and the current market.  I told her we would be willing to spend $15,000+ if needed to remodel, paint, etc. for selling (and we had specific suggestions).  She said not needed to most and that we would not get our money back.  In the end, we did some painting and we were prepared to stage the first floor.  While on the ‘private market’ (which you should ask about) starting late March, we had 7 showings (which she curated and prepped the other realtor) and 2 offers.  Start to finish was just three months (late March to closing at the end of June).  Very unusual and not necessarily what others will experience. 

My recommendation- invite Kati to your house to get acquainted and to get her assessment of the market and what she thinks you could sell for.  I am confident her recommendations will be measured and spot-on.

The most important thing I can say in closing is that by following Kati’s advice we netted more money and faster than if we have tried to control the process.”

I hope to see you there! If you can’t make it, don’t worry—just give me a call or send me an email and we’ll be sure to get you the information you need as well as an invitation to the next seminar we host.

In the meantime, if you have any questions about real estate, feel free to reach out. We’re here to be your real estate resource.

 

Click here for more information on the event!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/October/Youre+Invited+to+My+Upcoming+Home+Seller+Seminar.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/October/Youre+Invited+to+My+Upcoming+Home+Seller+Seminar.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What can you do to get your home ready for the market? Find out at my upcoming home seller seminar!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What can you do to get your home ready for the market? Find out at my upcoming home seller seminar!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Millennials Want When Looking for a Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-millennials-want-when-looking-for-a-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-10-04 16:55:38 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/October/What+Millennials+Want+When+Looking+for+a+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

In our Chicago North Shore real estate market, millennials make up the majority of homebuyers. They’re moving from the city, they’ve started a family, and they’re very busy. On top of all of this, they know what they’re looking for in a home. How can you help your home listing appeal to them?

Millennials usually look at homes online first, so it’s important that you have great pictures that show off your property. A good presentation means everything, so look into the services of a professional home photographer. If you want an idea of how the photos should look, think “HGTV.” That’s what they want to see, so go online and look at how HGTV presents homes. Their homes are always move-in ready, which appeals to millennials.

You also need to price your home properly, as millennials can easily find out how much homes are worth online. If they see your home is much more expensive than a similar house next door, they’ll disregard your listing.

“These buyers want their homes to be ready to live in from the beginning.”

Millennials are not hunting for huge houses, and they don’t want to do a ton of renovating right after they move in. These buyers want their homes to be ready to live in from the beginning, so make sure your home is move-in ready. Millennials are also very good about their budgets, so they typically spend under their limits. Instead of purchasing a $700,000 home, for example, they may buy a $550,000 house and spend the savings on updates.

If you have a large home that needs many mechanical updates and repairs, you’re going to have a hard time finding a millennial buyer. They’d rather put their money toward things like painting and decorating instead of home systems. Make sure you’re keeping your home maintained so you don’t have a long list of things to fix before you list.

Finally, millennials have a keen understanding of property taxes. They know these taxes are on the rise, which is why they’re actively avoiding large homes with large yards. This makes it important to fight your property taxes each year to keep them at a manageable level. Remember that if your property taxes are high, your home price will likely have to be lower.

Since millennials make up such a large part of the market now, it’s important to listen to your agent about how to appeal to these buyers. If you have any questions or would like more information, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to give you my recommendations and advice. Until then, I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/October/What+Millennials+Want+When+Looking+for+a+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/October/What+Millennials+Want+When+Looking+for+a+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Homebuyers today are more informed and money-savvy than ever, so it’s important to know how to appeal to them. Here’s what you should consider before listing your home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Homebuyers today are more informed and money-savvy than ever, so it’s important to know how to appeal to them. Here’s what you should consider before listing your home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Selling in the Fall Market vs. the Spring</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/selling-in-the-fall-market-vs-the-spring.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-09-23 13:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/September/Selling+in+the+Fall+Market+vs.+the+Spring.mp4</guid>
        <description>

All the time, people lament to me that because they missed the spring market, they might as well not put their house on the market until next year.

That is totally wrong, and today I’ll explain why.

People buy and sell homes all year long; it’s not like nobody buys or sells in the fall and winter! Mind you, the market is seasonal and tends to slow down, so while there aren’t as many people looking for houses, there’s also not as much inventory—that means less competition for you.

When you have one of the only two Colonial homes in your school district, for example, and a buyer has to move soon, that means yours is one of the two homes that that buyer will choose from.

If you want to sell your house, you have to list it. Don’t try to be super strategic about it in terms of timing. Remember, when you list in the springtime, you’ll be competing with a lot of fresh inventory, as well, and especially if you plan you test the price of your home.

“If you’re looking for a May, June, or July closing, I strongly recommend having your home on the market by the second week of January.”

Last year, I had five homes that sold in just the first week of January, and they had been on the market since August. So if you have a home on the market and you’re thinking of taking it off the market, don’t. Leave it on. If you don’t want to do showings during the holidays, then you don’t have to. Just cancel the showing; your agent can still collect the information from the buyer’s agent who tried to schedule the listing and then schedule a follow-up when your time is freer. If your house is totally off the market, then you won’t get any showings at all and you won’t sell your home.

You might have decided that the spring market is best for you because, for example, you don’t plan to close until June or July, so you’re just going to wait until after the Superbowl. Keep this in mind: It’s cold after the Superbowl! I don’t really abide by that strategy because you’ll still have to compete with all the other fresh inventory. Plus, if you list your home in March or April and you either miss the first rush or you’ve overpriced your home, you’ll only ride the market down until you have to start doing price reductions.

That’s why I prefer to list my houses earlier in the year, rather than later. If you’re looking for a May, June, or July closing, I strongly recommend having your home on the market by the second week of January. In case you end up selling your home before your initial plan, I’ll make sure to ask if you have temporary housing or someplace to go before you list—if you don’t, that would be a situation where it might be better to list a bit later in the year. However, the price may have to be a bit lower if you want an offer right away.

In the end, I always say it’s better to list your house when you’re ready to move; if you need to move now, then list your house now. There are always people looking for homes, even if certain times of the year are slower than others. But at least you’ll have the chance to sell—if you don’t list your home, then you are definitely not going to sell anything.

If you have any questions about buying or selling homes in the fall and spring months, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/September/Selling+in+the+Fall+Market+vs.+the+Spring.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/September/Selling+in+the+Fall+Market+vs.+the+Spring.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Sellers: Should you put your house on the market now or should you wait until the spring market? Today I’ll discuss.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Sellers: Should you put your house on the market now or should you wait until the spring market? Today I’ll discuss.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A 5-Step Seller Guide for Baby Boomers</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-5-step-seller-guide-for-baby-boomers.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-22 15:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/August/A+5-Step+Seller+Guide+for+Baby+Boomers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

→ Find out what your house is worth now→ Send me an email at info@spaniakteam.com to have us set up a market activity report for homes in your direct neighborhood or school district.

In my adventures in real estate, I’ve seen a lot of baby boomers—especially on the North Shore—who have been in their home for 20, 30, or as many as 40 years. Obviously, that means they also haven’t bought a home since then, and given that the market is rarely static, everything about it has changed: what buyers are looking for in a home and how they do it, in particular. 

When you do decide to sell, let’s talk about who will buy your home demographically-speaking.  Probably, it’ll be someone relatively close to your children’s age—maybe between 28 and 43 years old. 

For that reason, think about how your children operate and their current lifestyle. Are they working? Are they busy? Do they have children of their own? How do they communicate? It won’t take you long to realize that, yes, the market has gone through some profound changes since you last entered as a homebuyer. 

“Housing for empty-nesters in the North Shore is in short supply, so let’s put in the work now to get you in the home that’s right for you.”

Today’s buyers are extremely savvy and in-tune with current conditions. They’re more active than ever before—perusing Zillow, Trulia, and Realtor sites like mine—and communicating via social media. Because of that, they won’t be easily fooled into believing that your home is worth considerably more than your neighbor’s, and the increased sharing of information has a lot to do with that. 

To get right to the point, buyers are looking at your listing’s pictures online and moving on if they don’t like what they see. In other words, your pictures must be good. But beyond that, your product must be good as well. 

With that in mind, it’s important to first get a complete picture of your home’s market value. To help you get started, our team offers an automated assessment here that will produce a rough estimate of what your home is worth. 

Then, get in touch with your real estate professional. I’d be more than happy to visit you and your property three to five years before you plan to put your home on the market and advise you on what preparations you’ll need to make in the meantime.  

Thirdly, you’ll need to create a custom marketing strategy. It’s super simple: Go to our website and we’ll set up a strategy based on neighboring, similar properties. 

Although it often goes unconsidered, you have to plan for all possibilities. No matter how skilled your agent is, none of us can predict what the market has in store. We do know that the market will pay what your home is worth, so you must be willing to adapt and understand that you might not be able to achieve the sale price you set out to achieve. Communicate with everyone who’s part of the process and be honest with your agent if your valuation is lower than expected. We’ll see what we can do to help you sell at the desired price, but you need to trust your agent and the resources available to you. 

Fifth and finally, start looking now! The sooner you get your home search underway, the better. Simply send me an email to Info@SpaniakTeam.com and we can get a temporary search going. Housing for empty-nesters in the North Shore is in short supply, so let’s put in the work now to get you in the home that’s right for you. 

If you have any questions or would some help getting the process started, please call or text me at 847-379-8813 or send me an email at Info@SpaniakTeam.com. I hope to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/August/A+5-Step+Seller+Guide+for+Baby+Boomers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/August/A+5-Step+Seller+Guide+for+Baby+Boomers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re a baby boomer who’s thinking about selling your home, today’s message is just for you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re a baby boomer who’s thinking about selling your home, today’s message is just for you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>July 2019 North Shore Market Update</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/july-2019-north-shore-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-06 13:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/August/July+2019+North+Shore+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re more than halfway through 2019, which means now is the perfect time for another update on our North Shore real estate market. We’ll cover all the relevant trends buyers, sellers, and homeowners in our area should know.

For a more in-depth look at these trends, be sure to follow along in today’s video or check out our market reports below. 

Let’s start by looking at median sales prices over the past decade. In 2009, when our market was just beginning to decline, the median sales price in our North Shore market was $575,000. Now, the median sales price in our area is $525,000. The average sales price for July 2019, meanwhile, was $631,835. 

“Now that our market has recovered, inventory has increased as a result.”

But what about the number of homes for sale?

In January of 2009, there were 3,523 homes available in our North Shore market. When our market hit bottom in 2014, the number of available properties was cut in half, with just above 1,500 properties listed at that time. Now that our market has recovered, inventory has increased as a result. We had 2,266 available properties on our North Shore Market this July. Put another way, we had approximately 17 months’ worth of supply in 2009, but just 6.8 months’ worth this July. 

And because of the comparatively low levels of supply we’re now seeing, the average amount of time homes are spending on the market has also dropped. As of this July, the average days on market in the North Shore was 119. Homes still aren’t selling as quickly as they do in other markets, but this is a significant drop from the 213-day average we saw in late 2009. 

In other positive news, the number of closed homes has also increased in the last decade. In January of 2009, just 2,240 homes sold. This July, that number nearly doubled, with 3,934 homes closing that month. 

Homes have also become more affordable over that period. Between March of 2009 and July of 2019, the median price per square foot in our market has dropped from $242 to $216. 

And given the high number of new listings hitting our market, with 9,164 new properties going live this July, home prices are likely to drop even further. 

Of course, all of the figures we’ve discussed today only give a general overview of our North Shore real estate market. If you have any other questions, would like more information, or would like to discuss how your specific neighborhood has developed over time, please feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.

North Shore Stats:

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/R2oz-67UMedian Sales Price

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/R2oL-4JpAverage Sales Price

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/R2oM-9pHomes for Sale

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/R2oW-GAMNew Listings

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/R2op-xqdAverage Market Time

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/R2ov-5uXUnder Contract

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/R2o9-aJP% Last List (Closed) Average

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/R2oc-889Closed Sales

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/R2oG-vm5% Original List (Closed)

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/R2IB-VHvMedian Price Per Square Foot

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/R2Id-zLqAverage Price Per Square Foot

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/R2I2-bC5Contract to Close Average

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/R2I7-hdqDollar Volume

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/R2IZ-EHcListing to Contract Average

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/R2IY-OZNShows to Contract Median

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/R2IF-aFgShows to Contract Average

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/R2IR-F00Months Supply

https://mred.stats.10kresearch.com/infoserv/s-v1/R2Iw-aZxShows Per Listing
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/August/July+2019+North+Shore+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/August/July+2019+North+Shore+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How has our North Shore market changed over the last decade? Let’s discuss.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How has our North Shore market changed over the last decade? Let’s discuss.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Is the Biggest Mistake Sellers Make?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-is-the-biggest-mistake-sellers-make.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-21 14:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/June/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Is+the+Biggest+Mistake+Sellers+Make_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Sellers are prone to making a lot of mistakes. Pricing is one of the biggest, but it’s not the biggest. In my opinion, the biggest mistake sellers make is not listening to their real estate agent.

If you are working with an experienced real estate professional, you really need to listen to their advice. Plenty of people out there think they know better than their real estate agent, and that’s fine, but the truth is that they really don’t. 

“You’ve got to listen to your real estate agent.”

We’re in a tough situation because although we are salespeople, we are also consultants. Some people agents only give advice that will help their own bottom line, but this will never be the case if you work with a reputable professional. The advice we give our clients is based on experience and knowledge and is designed to help you sell for the most money possible in the shortest period of time.

You’ve got to listen to your real estate agent. If they’re telling you something over and over again, take a step back, listen, and realize that they know what they’re doing. 

If you have any questions about your specific situation or about real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/June/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Is+the+Biggest+Mistake+Sellers+Make_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/June/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Is+the+Biggest+Mistake+Sellers+Make_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The biggest mistake home sellers can make has nothing to do with pricing. It’s ignoring the advice of an experienced real estate professional.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The biggest mistake home sellers can make has nothing to do with pricing. It’s ignoring the advice of an experienced real estate professional.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Do Homes That Aren’t Updated Fail to Sell?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-do-homes-that-arent-updated-fail-to-sell.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-24 11:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/May/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+Do+Homes+That+Arent+Updated+Fail+to+Sell_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Why do homes that aren’t updated fail to sell?

Over the last three years or so, the buyer pool in our market has changed. Between balancing their work life and family life, many millennials don’t have time to make upgrades to a home after they buy it. Because of this, they prefer houses that are move-in ready, and this preference has influenced other buyer demographics. 

HGTV has also changed the real estate industry in that everyone expects their next home to be something like what they’ve seen on that channel. 

This means if your home isn’t updated once you put it on the market, buyers are going to cut it out of their search completely. They’re not interested in looking at a house that doesn’t evoke an emotional reaction. 

“If your home isn’t updated once you put it on the market, buyers are going to cut it out of their search completely.”

These days, buyers decide how much they want to invest in a house before buying it. Previously, if a buyer could spend up to a certain amount on a home, they would spend every dollar of that amount and, over time, do the extra work on the home afterward to get it to look how they wanted. This trend has caused homes values to dip. 

Even if you have made updates to your home, you’re not in the clear yet. If those updates are 10 years old or older, they’re probably outdated. Unfortunately, many buyers are willing to sacrifice quality for trendiness. 

If you’re not sure what to update or what “updating” really means for your home, give me a call and I’d be happy to come out to your home and give you a free evaluation. Don’t spend any money unless you’re absolutely sure you’ll see a return on your investment. 

If you have any more questions about this or any other real estate topic, feel free to reach out to me as well. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/May/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+Do+Homes+That+Arent+Updated+Fail+to+Sell_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/May/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+Why+Do+Homes+That+Arent+Updated+Fail+to+Sell_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If your home isn’t updated when you put it on the market, you’ll have a hard time selling it. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If your home isn’t updated when you put it on the market, you’ll have a hard time selling it. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can A Seller Tell a Good Offer From One That Isn’t?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-can-a-seller-tell-a-good-offer-from-one-that-isnt.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-07 14:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/May/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+A+Seller+Tell+a+Good+Offer+From+One+That+Isn%E2%80%99t%3F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Since going on the market, your home has been on the receiving end of multiple offers. How will you know which offer to take in this scenario? A better question might even be: How can I discern a strong offer from those that aren’t? 

Let’s say you’ve set your price at $200,000 and a buyer comes in offering $225,000. At face value, this seems like a strong offer that you shouldn’t pass up. The reality is that buyers can sometimes let their emotions get in the way of sound judgment; they might throw out an offer and not realize that they’re probably overpaying until you’ve gone under contract. Consequently, they decide to withdraw their offer.  

By this point, you may have already made the mistake of accepting an offer like this with a few different buyers. Really, the highest priced offer isn’t always the best offer. The best offer, then, is the one that’s actually going to close.  

This is where your agent comes in: They should be able to pick up on clues during the showings, the offer process, negotiations, and inspection. A professional, experienced agent will be adept at reading the buyer.

“The best offer is the one that’s actually going to close.”

Now, if the offer price is too high, it probably won’t appraise, which means the buyer will not be able to obtain a mortgage. One of three things will happen at that point: They’ll have to come up with additional money, you’ll have to go lower in price (which usually happens), or you’ll have to reenter the market; all three of these options are less than ideal. 

A cash offer way above asking price, on the other hand, can be good because you won’t need to bring in an appraiser; you’ll want to know if this is in the contract or not. 

As a seller, try not to be enticed by an offer that’s a few thousand dollars higher; a good offer with the highest probability of closing should take priority. Once you’ve made up your mind to take an offer and you’ve gotten through attorney review, the emotional fatigue will give you eagerness to close. 

What if a buyer includes a mortgage contingency in their offer? If this is the case, keep in mind that the buyer will have that contingency all the way up until closing. This means there will be some uncertainty until the day comes.         

Between an offer that’s $200,000 in cash and another that’s $225,000 with a mortgage contingency, you should strongly consider taking the cash offer because you can be sure that the deal will close. 

Another thing to look for in an offer is the behavior of the buyer. Plainly put, you want to work with an “easy” buyer. What do I mean by that? Well, some seller clients and I recently worked with a buyer who had been to the home three or four times and was hung up on one item, in particular. 

They asked about the item to no end, and it completely turned my sellers off. When it came time to select an offer, my seller didn’t even consider this buyer’s because of how difficult they had been. This is the type of buyer you’d do well to avoid. 

I hope today’s message helped you better understand what kind of offer you should look for. If you have any questions about this or about anything else real estate-related, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/May/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+A+Seller+Tell+a+Good+Offer+From+One+That+Isn%E2%80%99t%3F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/May/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+A+Seller+Tell+a+Good+Offer+From+One+That+Isn%E2%80%99t%3F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You may feel like you’ve found a winning buyer for your home, but today’s message may cause you to reconsider.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You may feel like you’ve found a winning buyer for your home, but today’s message may cause you to reconsider.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>We’re Looking for New People to Sell Real Estate</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/were-looking-for-new-people-to-sell-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-22 15:35:13 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/April/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+Were+Looking+for+New+People+to+Sell+Real+Estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Does anyone in your circle of family, friends, co-workers, or acquaintances want to sell real estate?

We are always looking for great additions to the team, and we’re not just searching for people with experience in real estate—we’re looking for anyone who is personable, authentic, great with sales, hard-working, and self-accountable.

Here at the Spaniak Team, we offer the opportunity to learn, grow, get leads, and start out your career using a base of people you know.

“On our team, we think that you should be making at least $50,000 in your first year.”

A lot of times, agents get into the business and it takes a few years in order for them to start making money. However, on our team, we think that you should be making at least $50,000 in your first year. In your second year, we hope that you can even make as much as $150,000 or more.

So think about it: Do you know anyone who would be a great fit on our team? If so, please forward this email to them. You can access the information about how to apply here.

It’s okay if you don’t know of anyone right now—but keep this in mind for the future. If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/April/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+Were+Looking+for+New+People+to+Sell+Real+Estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/April/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+Were+Looking+for+New+People+to+Sell+Real+Estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Instead of answering a question, today I want to ask YOU one: Do you know anyone who wants to sell real estate?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Instead of answering a question, today I want to ask YOU one: Do you know anyone who wants to sell real estate?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Guide for First-Time Homebuyers</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-guide-for-first-time-homebuyers.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-28 15:38:11 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/March/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Guide+for+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re a first-time homebuyer, how do you go about finding a home? Here are a few tips that will help ease you into the process and make sure you get to the closing table with as little hassle as possible. 

First, start looking around online and researching local agents in the area. Some of the bigger real estate sites like Zillow might not be updated all the time, so it’s a good idea to connect with some local agents early on.

After that, tour the areas you want to live in and narrow them down. During this time, you’ll also want to start interviewing agents. I know a lot of millennials nowadays insist that they can buy a home on their own, and maybe that’s true, but agents can provide you with a lot of information you otherwise won’t have. 

For example, they can help advise you on what you’re looking for and steer you in the right direction so you don’t waste your time looking at houses that aren’t a good fit. After all, they’ve very likely been in many of the houses in the area you’re looking to live in. 

On a related note, remember that a home’s online pictures don’t always tell the whole story. A lot of people don’t want to waste their time looking at homes that don’t look great in pictures, but you can’t count on these pictures to tell you exactly how a house looks or whether it’s really in an area you want to live in. That’s why it’s important to see them in person. If you’re just starting out and you’re moving from the city into the suburbs, I recommend attending at least 10 open houses before you start narrowing down your options. 

Another thing you want to do early on in the process is to get in touch with a lender and get pre-approved—there’s nothing worse than shopping for homes without knowing what you can afford. 

“No matter what price range you’re buying in, every home will have at least one thing you don’t like about it.”

Also, keep in mind that no matter what price range you’re buying in, every home will have at least one thing you don’t like about it. None of them will be perfect—you can probably get about 80% or 90% of what you’re looking for, but not 100%. 

After you move on to the inspection phase, remember it’s normal for a few things to need to be repaired. I’ve seen a lot of home inspections go awry because the buyers insisted that everything had to be clean and in perfect working order, and that’s just now what homeownership is. 

With that in mind, keep your inspection requests to non-functioning items such as a leaking roof or a furnace that’s not working. The contract you sign only allows you to ask for requests on major non-functioning items anyway. In other words, if you come across a furnace that’s 30 years old but it still works, you can’t ask for a new unit.

This is why it’s important to know how old the home’s mechanical systems are and take that into account before writing your offer. If the roof is, say, 25 years old, there’s a good chance you’ll need to replace it within the next five years. If you wait for the inspection to find that type of thing out, you’ll have to renegotiate the purchase price, which rarely ends well. 

If you have any more questions about being a first-time homebuyer or you have any other real estate needs at all, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/March/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Guide+for+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Videos/2019/March/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Guide+for+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Buying a home for the first time? Here’s what you need to know to make the process as smooth as possible.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Buying a home for the first time? Here’s what you need to know to make the process as smooth as possible.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Common Home Seller Mistakes That You Must Avoid</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-common-home-seller-mistakes-that-you-must-avoid.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-13 12:16:37 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

What are the biggest mistakes home sellers make when selling their homes? There are three, in particular, that you need to avoid. 

The first is overpricing your home. If your home’s price doesn’t compare with the rest of the homes that are available in your neighborhood, people won’t even look at it, even though it might look identical to those other homes. Once in a while, you might get a lowball offer, but serious buyers typically don’t throw out lowball offers because, with all the information that’s available online, they’ll know what your home should be priced at. 

In any case, you don’t want to wait for a lowball offer, because that buyer will be in the driver’s seat during negotiations. If you agree to their offer, they’ll know you have nobody else looking at the home, so they’ll start making more and more demands. What’s more, you’ll be so exhausted by the whole situation at that point that you’ll end up selling for much less than what you could’ve gotten.

“To avoid overpricing your home, look at it through the eyes of a buyer.”

To avoid overpricing your home, look at it through the eyes of a buyer. Look at all the comparable properties in your neighborhood and be objective. Remember, your home is only worth what a buyer will pay for it. 

The second mistake is not countering an initial offer. Some buyers get emotional over an offer that they think is too low and then decide not to counter it. As I tell my clients, you should always make a counteroffer. Remember that your first offer will likely be your highest offer, and it’s not where you start—it’s where you end. Your agent will know what your home’s worth, so they’ll be able to advise you on what type of counteroffer to make. 

Just because you want a certain price doesn’t mean you’re going to get it. If you’re dead-set on a specific number, it’s important to consider what that little bit of extra money is worth to you compared to the comfort of being done with your home sale. 

The third mistake is restricting showing access to the public. If, for instance, you require a 24-hour notice to show your home, that makes your agent’s job a lot more difficult because buyers move quickly in our market. I recommend not putting any restrictions on your showings. If you get a showing request, you can always just decline it, and hopefully your agent will be able to reschedule with the prospective buyer. 

As always, if you have any questions about this topic or you have any other real estate needs I can help you with, feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d love to speak with you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re putting your home on the market, there are three common mistakes you need to avoid.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re putting your home on the market, there are three common mistakes you need to avoid.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Key Tips to Selling Your Home on Your Own</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/key-tips-to-selling-your-home-on-your-own.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-26 13:06:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Do+You+Sell+Your+Home+on+Your+Own_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How do you sell your home on your own? 

First of all, you should know that doing this doesn’t necessarily mean you’re going to make more money. A lot of people assume that if they don’t hire an agent and don’t have to pay a commission fee, they’ll make more money, but there are plenty of savvy buyers out there who know how to take advantage of FSBOs.

“There are a lot of steps involved in selling a home, and you could be risking a lot of money if you don’t do it the right way.”

That’s why it’s important that you do it the right way. By this, I mean there are certain steps you need to take and factors to take into consideration. For your convenience, I’ve provided timestamps of each of these steps from the video above so you can skip ahead at your leisure: 

0:48—Make sure your house looks great 1:12—Get professional photos taken1:59—Price your home correctly 3:01—Don’t reduce your price because you don’t have an agent 5:27—The pros and cons of paying a broker fee to the buyer’s agent6:39—Put a sign in your yard 7:00—Dealing with agents who call you7:47—Don’t list your home on the MLS as FSBO

There are a lot of steps involved in selling a home, and you could be risking a lot of money if you don’t do it the right way, so make sure you do your research and talk to as many professionals as possible. 

If you have any questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Do+You+Sell+Your+Home+on+Your+Own_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Do+You+Sell+Your+Home+on+Your+Own_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There’s a lot that goes into selling a home, but if you’re going to do it on your own, here are the key steps you need to take.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There’s a lot that goes into selling a home, but if you’re going to do it on your own, here are the key steps you need to take.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Real Reason Everyone Is Moving Away From Illinois</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-real-reason-everyone-is-moving-away-from-illinois.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-18 14:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you’ve been paying attention to our market, you might have noticed an interesting trend: An increasing number of people are moving out of our state. Why is this happening? The reason is simple, and we’ll get to the bottom of it in today’s message. 

Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure: 

0:51 - Real data on the number of residents who have left Illinois in recent years

1:39 - The first reason people are leaving Illinois: weather

2:12 - The second reason people are leaving: corrupt government practices

4:01 - The third reason people are leaving: increasing property taxes

4:24 - Why I care, and why you should too

6:25 - What you can do about it

7:45 - A few closing words

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Illinois is rapidly losing its population, and today I’m going to give some insight into why this is happening.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Illinois is rapidly losing its population, and today I’m going to give some insight into why this is happening.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What to Do If You Can’t Decide Whether to Move or Remodel</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-to-do-if-you-cant-decide-whether-to-move-or-remodel.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-11 11:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

With spring just around the corner, now is the perfect time to discuss a question I always receive during these early months of the year: Should you remodel or should you move?

If you’ve been thinking about taking on a total rehaul of your kitchen, tearing down a wall, or doing any number of other major remodeling projects, this is a question you may want to ask yourself. You may find that the easier solution is to find a new home that better suits your evolving needs, rather than trying to change your current one to elicit the same effect. 

The first thing to realize is that you can talk to a real estate agent without necessarily committing to purchasing a home. Many agents are more than happy to speak with you about your circumstances and advise you as to what steps you should take. They can also get you set up on an automated home search, which will alert you when local homes that match your criteria become available. 

After getting set up on this search, you should begin developing a stronger relationship with your agent. This person should become someone you know, like, and trust—someone who truly cares about your best interests and will be honest with you regarding any questions or goals you discuss with them. You should partner with someone who, when you approach them with a question like whether you should remodel or move, won’t default to the latter option just because it would benefit them.

“Straddling the line between these two options indefinitely won’t put you any closer to accomplishing either one.”

When I sign a buyer’s agreement with a client, for example, I don’t pressure them into moving forward at a pace they aren’t comfortable with. My focus isn’t on getting clients through the pipeline as quickly as possible—it’s on finding and leveraging opportunities for the people who have entrusted me with their real estate goals. Buyer’s agreements aren’t designed to be used against you. These documents merely exist to allow you and your agent to work together as effectively as possible. 

Of course, if you are on the fence about whether to remodel or move, you should speak to a contractor and get price estimates from them, as well. Between your contractor and your agent, you should be able to get a good idea of how much each option will cost.

Then, after doing your due diligence, the last step is to pick a path and go down it. Straddling the line between these two options indefinitely won’t put you any closer to accomplishing either one. Eventually, you need to commit and stick with your choice. And, assuming you’ve followed all of the steps I outlined for you today, you should be able to move forward with confidence. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you can’t decide whether to remodel your current home or move into a new one, following these steps will help you choose a path and stick to it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you can’t decide whether to remodel your current home or move into a new one, following these steps will help you choose a path and stick to it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Downsizing in the North Shore is Difficult</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-downsizing-in-the-north-shore-is-difficult.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-13 13:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Difficulties+of+Downsizing+in+Our+Local+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

People who want to downsize in the North Shore may encounter a number of issues with doing so. Why? Well, many of these people currently live in decently large, Colonial-style homes, and would prefer something similar when the time comes to downsize. This means they probably won’t be interested in a tiny condo without a view. 

Unfortunately, there is very limited inventory in our market right now that suits the needs of these kinds of people. Many such buyers have a large portion of their money tied up in their current property, and finding a new property that fits their wants and needs may cost more money than their home is worth. There are very few homes available on the North Shore for under $500,000. 

Empty nesters, in particular, may soon be faced with a crisis-like situation as a result of these factors. This is exactly why those considering downsizing in our area must connect with a Realtor early on. It will also be crucial to speak with a mortgage broker, as lending laws have changed. This could impact retirees’ ability to obtain a mortgage. 

“Those considering downsizing in our area must connect with a Realtor early on.”

Those without an active source of income will often need to sell their current home to afford their next one, which can lead to a complicated closing and weaken your position as a buyer. A bridge loan may be your best option in terms of how you will finance your purchase. 

Another reason it will be essential to speak with a Realtor when considering downsizing is that they will help you gain a better idea of what such a move would actually mean for your lifestyle. 

Those not used to having a single-story home may find it difficult to adjust after coming from a home with more living space, for example. And mentally adjusting isn’t enough. You will need to make tangible adjustments, as well, such as getting rid of extra belongings. Chances are, your children (if you have them) won’t want these items. It’s best to donate or trash the things you don’t want, or don’t have room for, in your new home. 

With all of the steps involved, downsizing could be a three- to five-year process. It will certainly be taxing at times, but we would be happy to help. We would love to serve as your real estate professionals and guide you through the process. We can also connect you to other local professionals, such as movers and photographers. It is our goal to make your move as smooth as possible, despite the current difficulties faced by those in your position. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Difficulties+of+Downsizing+in+Our+Local+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Difficulties+of+Downsizing+in+Our+Local+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you are looking to downsize, there are a number of critical considerations you’ll need to keep in mind during this process.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you are looking to downsize, there are a number of critical considerations you’ll need to keep in mind during this process.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Does Roberts Heating and Air Serve Our Community?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-does-roberts-heating-and-air-serve-our-community.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-10 10:04:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+Roberts+Heating+and+Air.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m excited to be joined by Keith Miller of Roberts Heating and Air in Northbrook to talk about his life, his career, and his business. 

Roberts Heating and Air was started by Glenn Roberts in 1979. In 1983, he asked Keith to join him and in 1990, Keith became a partner when they moved into their first shop. Early on, they did mostly residential service work and a bit of residential construction work. These days, they still do residential work, but have also added commercial work, retrofit replacement, and pretty much everything that has to do with heating and air conditioning.

They’re currently located at 1847 Raymond Dr. in Northbrook, where Keith and Glenn both live. Their team consists of about 20 members and includes those who assist with daily office work and customer service requests, as well as field employees like installers and service technicians.

The No. 1 question that Keith says he hears from his clients is, “Is my equipment safe?” To answer the question, they like to take their clients through a tune-up to come up with an answer. It all starts with simple maintenance.

“Glenn Roberts founded Roberts Heating and Air in 1979.”

One of the biggest issues they see from their customers is equipment failure. A lot of this can be solved with routine maintenance, but anytime equipment fails, the pressure is on—especially in extreme temperatures. Roberts prides themselves on being able to give same-day service to their clients.

Keith and his team believe that honesty is the best policy. They make their decisions and help their clients make decisions based on what’s best for them in the long term. This includes recommending repairs, replacements, and tune-ups when needed to minimize costs over time.

This family company is owned by two Northbrook natives who know what’s going on every day and are trying to follow up the best they can in any way with great, 24-7-365 service.

If you have heating and air needs that you need assistance with or if you have any questions, you can reach out to Roberts Heating and Air at (847) 272-5836 or at their website. Ask them about their Cool Cash Rebate of up to $2,350 on qualifying systems.

If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email today. I look forward to hearing from you soon.


</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+Roberts+Heating+and+Air.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+Roberts+Heating+and+Air.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Keith Miller has been with Roberts Heating and Air since 1983. I recently had a great conversation with him about his career and the journey he has taken.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Keith Miller has been with Roberts Heating and Air since 1983. I recently had a great conversation with him about his career and the journey he has taken.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Seriously Should You View Your Home’s Zestimate?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-seriously-should-you-view-your-homes-zestimate.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-13 11:51:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Important+Are+Zillows+Zestimates.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What is a Zestimate? As a home seller, is it something you need to put a lot of stock in?

First, a Zestimate is Zillow’s formula for calculating your home’s value. Zillow doesn’t reveal exactly how the formula works, but we do know that it’s based on tax records, comparable neighborhood home sales, homes that are active on the market, and other similar factors. 

Is your house actually worth what a Zestimate says it’s worth, though? No—it’s worth whatever a buyer is willing to pay for it. A Zestimate is a good starting point in understanding your home’s value, but buyers don’t always look at a home’s Zestimate when looking at the home itself, and they’re generally educated enough to know to take a home’s Zestimate with a grain of salt.

“A home’s Zestimate really isn’t that significant.”

As an agent, if I’m giving a home a market valuation, I can pull its estimated value from a number of different websites and pretty much tell what kind of house it is by looking at that price, but that price won’t tell you what kind of updates the home has, how it’s decorated, or if it’s cluttered on the inside. In other words, a home’s Zestimate really isn’t that significant. 

You can, however, try to make your home’s Zestimate more accurate. All you have to do is go Zillow, “claim” your house, and change any details that are incorrect. Since we don’t know exactly how a Zestimate is calculated, though, this can sometimes be more frustrating than it’s worth. At the end of the day, there’s not much you can do to influence your home’s Zestimate. 

If you have any more questions about Zillow’s Zestimates or you have any other real estate needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Important+Are+Zillows+Zestimates.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Important+Are+Zillows+Zestimates.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>As a home seller, your home’s Zestimate isn’t that significant. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>As a home seller, your home’s Zestimate isn’t that significant. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What You Can Learn at My Seller Seminar</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-you-can-learn-at-my-seller-seminar.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-31 08:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+Youre+Invited+to+My+Next+Home+Selling+Seminar.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’m excited to announce that my next home selling seminar is happening on Monday, November 12 at the Northbrook Public Library from 6 p.m. to 8 p.m. If you’re thinking of selling your home, you won’t want to miss it. 

What can you learn by attending this seminar? Well, last month we hosted a seller seminar that received a great turnout, and I was able to share some of the most important tricks of the trade with those in attendance, including:


  What to look for in an agent
  How to properly prepare your home for the market
  How to sell quickly and for top dollar 


To dive a little deeper and give you a better idea of what you can learn, I have a couple of clips from this seminar I’d like to share with you, starting at 0:46 in the video above.

“The first four weeks your home is on the market is the time period it will see the most activity.”

In the first clip, I emphasize the importance of pricing your home correctly from the very beginning. The first four weeks your home is on the market is the time period it will see the most activity, and you want to be under contract during that time. If you price your home too high, you won’t attract any buyer attention or receive any offers until several weeks later. By that point, they’ll assume they’ll be able to get a good deal on your home, and they’ll probably be right, because by that time you’ll be exhausted from the whole process. 

The second clip explains how your home’s appraised value influences your sale. Appraisers value your home by looking at the numbers. By that I mean its square footage, lot size, year built, etc. They’ll look at its updates, too, but only if those updates happened within the last 10 years. 

Your home’s appraised value can be either higher or lower than its market value, but the appraised value is the number the buyer will have to meet to buy the house. If the buyer is in the middle of getting a mortgage but your house doesn’t appraise at its market value, one of three things will happen: You’ll have to reduce the home’s price to meet the appraised value, the buyer will have to pay more to cover the difference, or you’ll have to put the home back on the market. 

To register for this seminar and get all the details about this great event, click here.

If you can’t make it, just shoot me an email and I’d be glad to send you the full powerpoint presentation. Or, I can always come to your house and give you a one-on-one presentation. 

If you have any questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+Youre+Invited+to+My+Next+Home+Selling+Seminar.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+Youre+Invited+to+My+Next+Home+Selling+Seminar.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You’re invited to attend my upcoming seller seminar on November 12. There, you’ll learn what you need to do to sell your home quickly and for top dollar.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You’re invited to attend my upcoming seller seminar on November 12. There, you’ll learn what you need to do to sell your home quickly and for top dollar.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Here’s What the Market Is Doing Right Now</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/heres-what-the-market-is-doing-right-now.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-05 09:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+the+Market+Doing%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I hosted a fantastic home seller seminar last night where I was able to talk openly and honestly to potential home sellers. One of the first slides I put up during the seminar answered the question, “What does the market look like now?” and I’d like to share that with you today. 

As you can see in the video above, new listings on the North Shore have continually increased since the beginning of 2015. At that point, there was very little inventory. When the public started hearing that so many buyers were having a difficult time finding homes, that’s when they started listing homes again and that trend has continued to this day.

“If you are planning on selling in this market, both pricing and preparation are key.”

In another chart, you can see that closed sales continued to increase from 2015 through 2017, before dropping this year. If you are thinking about selling any time in the next year, it’s important to talk to a real estate agent. You probably don’t want to wait until next spring. There might be a huge spike in inventory and you might have a more difficult time selling.

If you are planning on selling, both preparation and pricing are key. Your home has to look its best and it has to be priced correctly. If it’s not, you could lose tens of thousands of dollars on your final sale price. 

If you are considering selling in 2019, we’d love for you to attend our next seller seminar. If you have any other questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+the+Market+Doing%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Kati+Spaniak/Chicago+North+Shore+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+the+Market+Doing%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>A lot of people are wondering about the real estate market and what it looks like right now. Keep reading to find out exactly what’s going on.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>A lot of people are wondering about the real estate market and what it looks like right now. Keep reading to find out exactly what’s going on.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Waiting to List in the Spring Your Best Option?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/is-waiting-to-list-in-the-spring-your-best-option.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 10:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

One question I get asked a lot right now is whether you should wait until spring to list your home. Honestly, this isn’t a good idea. Today I want to take a look at why.

To start with, although the market isn’t as good as it is in the spring, people are always looking for homes. Therefore, if you have a home that you’re thinking about selling, now’s a better time to get it listed instead of later.

If you’re one of the people that is worried about a long list time, you should know that this is a fact of the game right now. Homes are taking a lot longer to sell and there are very few homes going under contract within one week, so looking at the number of days on market doesn’t mean as much anymore.

If your home is already on the market, you should keep it listed. Taking it off the market for the winter isn’t a good idea, but keeping it on and expecting fewer showings is.

“Listing your home now and keeping it listed through the holidays is to your advantage because you don’t have to compete with other listings and still have potential buyers.”

Over the last couple of years I’ve seen a trend of people coming onto the market in the spring. By putting your home on the market then, you could run into too much inventory and be stuck on the market into June, July, or even August. Then, you may end up doing a price reduction.

Instead of doing this, you should list early and expect to remain on the market for a longer time frame. This way you won’t end up in July worrying about if you can sell before school starts.

Listing your home now and keeping it listed through the holidays is to your advantage because you don’t have to compete with other listings and still have potential buyers.

If you have any additional questions about listing or buying now, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Should you wait to list until the spring? Maybe not.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Should you wait to list until the spring? Maybe not.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Join Us on September 26 for Our Seller Seminar</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/join-us-on-september-26-for-our-seller-seminar.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 10:38:04 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I’m going to tell you why you should come to our seller seminar. If you’re thinking about moving at any time in the next three to five years, we’d love to talk to you.

We’ll be talking about a ton of things, including:


  How to put your house on the market
  The best time to put your house on the market
  What’s most important in selling your home
  How to price your house
  How to get your home ready to sell
  Whether you should get an inspection before you put your home on the market
  How to time your move if you need to sell before you buy


“If you’re considering a move in the next three to five years, we’d love for you to join us.”

This is a great opportunity for you to come out, hear from some industry experts, and be able to talk to me about your personal situation.

The seminar will be on September 26 from 6:00 p.m. to 8:00 p.m. at the Northbrook Public Library in the Pollack Room. It’s free to attend and you can register for the event here. We hope you can make it!

If you have any questions in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We have a seller seminar coming up on September 26 and we’d love for you to join us. Here’s what you can expect from the event.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We have a seller seminar coming up on September 26 and we’d love for you to join us. Here’s what you can expect from the event.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Difference between Good and Great</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-difference-between-good-and-great.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 10:33:43 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

What makes the Spaniak team great, rather than simply “good?”

Many of you may know the book “Good to Great” by Jim Collins. I’m currently reading this fantastic book about what makes companies great, rather than good, for the second time.

Allow me to share just one example from the book: The Stockdale Paradox, which is based on Jim Stockdale. A prisoner of war in Vietnam for eight years, Jim Stockdale was tortured over 20 times. While other POWs were optimistic about getting out, he knew the realities of his situation.

I was able to tie this story back to my business and team. A lot of times I will go into a house and do a market evaluation without really thinking about the realities of the situation. Sellers love to hear that you think you’ll be able to sell their home at a desirable price.

Still, while you may believe that you can sell your home for that price, you need to think about the realities of the situation. I think my team’s willingness to be honest is what makes us great.

“I am willing to walk into any house and be completely honest, whether or not I get the sale, about where I truly think your house is going to sell.”

I am willing to walk into any house and be completely honest about what price it should be listed at. As your consultant, I am going to be honest with you an make sure that you know the realities of the current market. We will talk it through and, if I think it is in your best interest not to sell and instead rent, I am going to talk to you about that tactfully.

This is because selling your home can be very traumatic and you want a real estate agent that is not just optimistic and tells you what you want to hear. You need the agent that is able to push back a little and explain the reality but still be able to do what we can to get your house sold, especially if you have to move because of finances, relocation, divorce, etc.

This is a very serious line of work and I take my job very seriously. This is what I think makes us go from good to great. I think we are great because I can tell you the honest truth and tell you how to get your house sold.

If you have any questions or are interested in buying or selling with my great team, please feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I am going to explain to you why I think that the Spaniak Team is great.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I am going to explain to you why I think that the Spaniak Team is great.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Let a Multiple Offer Situation Get the Best of You</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-let-a-multiple-offer-situation-get-the-best-of-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 10:28:55 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Recently, our Illinois market has become slightly less competitive than it was in the past. But it is still fairly common for a listing to receive multiple offers.

With that said, how can buyers and sellers succeed in multiple offer situations?

Let’s start with what sellers should do. First of all, it’s really important to not focus solely on dollar signs. Sellers should also look at all the terms of the contract. These will be as significant as the offer price because they reveal important information about the overall quality of the offer.

Some buyers may make emotional bids they can’t actually afford. By looking closely at their offer, sellers and their agents will easily be able to discern if this is the case. Accepting an emotionally motivated offer can often lead to a broken deal, as many buyers will back out once remorse starts to kick in.

It’s also important to compare a buyer’s offer against your home’s appraised value. Too large a disparity between these figures will lead to one of three scenarios: You will either have to lower the price, the buyer will have to pay the difference in cash, or you will have to put the property back on the market.

“The bottom line is that you must work closely with a trusted agent when choosing from between multiple offers.”

There is also a fourth option: A truly serious buyer may be willing to waive the appraisal contingency.

The bottom line is that you must work closely with a trusted agent when choosing between multiple offers. This will be the key to unlocking your success.

As for buyers, my best advice for tackling multiple offer situations is to not play games. The important thing is to collaborate with your agent in determining what you’re truly willing to pay for a home. That said, price isn’t everything.

Figuring out what’s most important to a seller will help you to craft the most attractive offer possible. Sometimes an offer that allows the seller more time in the home may win out over one with a higher price. It’s all about what motivates the person selling the property.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you concerned about how to navigate a multiple offer situation? Today I’ll be sharing my top advice for how buyers and sellers should approach this difficult scenario.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you concerned about how to navigate a multiple offer situation? Today I’ll be sharing my top advice for how buyers and sellers should approach this difficult scenario.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Blind Yourself to All the Opportunities in Our Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-blind-yourself-to-all-the-opportunities-in-our-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 10:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Our market is truly hot at the moment. But is it a buyer’s market or a seller’s market?

Ultimately, it depends on what kind of house you have. Illinois has seen many issues relating to property taxes, which tend to skew the market. Many people are selling their homes here and flocking to other states to either buy or rent.

Likely, you’ve been hearing that it’s a seller’s market nationwide. But here in the Chicagoland area, if you have high taxes, you’ll have a harder time selling your home, especially if it’s a more expensive one.

As a refresher, a buyer’s market would mean that there is a lot of inventory on the market from which buyers can choose. However, in reality, what buyers are looking for doesn’t actually exist.

The problem with buyers nowadays is that they’ve been so spoiled by things like HGTV and scouting homes online based on (beautiful) photography that they’re missing out on some fantastic deals. Some truly great homes might just need a fresh coat of paint, some wallpaper taken down, or some hardwood flooring put in. You have to get beyond what the pictures look like and actually go to the houses themselves.

“The problem with buyers nowadays is that they’ve been so spoiled by things like HGTV and scouting homes online based on (beautiful) photography that they’re missing out on some fantastic deals.”

So, is it a seller’s market? It is if your house is gray and white, has an updated kitchen, and looks like it just came out of HGTV. You’ll have to anticipate what those in the market are looking for if you want top dollar for your home. If it’s not up to the buyers’ standards, your listing will spend a lot longer on the market and you won’t get quite as much as you might have otherwise.

Now, if you’re a buyer it’s also a buyer’s market. There is so much inventory out there that does need some work, but you can get it for a great deal.

Be sure to keep this in mind as you navigate the market, whether you’re looking to buy or sell a home. Reach out to your real estate professional sooner than later; they can give you advice about what upgrades to make to boost the overall value and appeal of your listing so you get the most money possible without wasting it on unnecessary upgrades.

If you don’t already have a current real estate agent helping you, I encourage you to reach out to me. The Spaniak Team can answer your questions and advise you on how you can best achieve your real estate goals.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Is it a buyer’s or a seller’s market? Well, here in Chicagoland, it actually sort of depends.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Is it a buyer’s or a seller’s market? Well, here in Chicagoland, it actually sort of depends.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Advantages of Working With a Real Estate Team</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-advantages-of-working-with-a-real-estate-team.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 10:19:03 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

“What’s the difference between a real estate team and a real estate agent?” This is a question I hear all the time.

The main difference is the customer service. If you work with an individual agent, they have to do everything at once. This includes running listing sheets, entering data, negotiating inspection requests, and much more. If they have more than three listings at a time, it’s hard for them to manage sleep, let alone the transactions themselves.

If you work with a real estate team like ours, there are multiple people servicing you at once. Our Director of Operations is responsible for managing the office, and our listing manager only focuses on selling and marketing our listings. They are constantly doing things like reaching out to agents to see if clients are interested in our homes, which puts the houses back on their radar. Feedback is important to us, and it’s one of the reasons that we’re set up like this. Individual agents simply don’t have time.

“There simply aren’t enough hours in the day for an individual agent to give you the attention you deserve.”

We also have a transaction coordinator, who takes the home from contract to close. Following up with attorneys, inspectors, appraisers, and the buyer’s agents are just a few things this person does. In addition to answering questions that both sellers and buyers have about their move. We have a runner who is also available at any time to complete tasks, such as meeting vendors or bringing listing sheets over. In addition, the buyer’s agents on our team are completely focused on helping homebuyers get the best service possible.

What do I do? First of all, I oversee the team while also understanding the market and what’s going on with it at a high level. I relay this information to my clients. I also spend a considerable amount of time talking about pricing with the seller and negotiating. These are the things which are most important to a transaction. This allows me time for my clients to get a hold of me. When they need something, they can reach out to me and I’m available.

The high level of customer service is undeniable with a team, and you simply can’t get the same level of service with an individual agent. While some individual agents can provide a high level of customer service there is so much to do that the math doesn’t add up. You won’t get the attention you need, want, or deserve. I think in the next 10 years, every real estate agent will be part of a team.

If you want to get ahead of the trend by working with our team, or if you just have any questions about the market or your house, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Many people are wondering whether they should hire an individual agent or a real estate team. Here is how the two differ.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Many people are wondering whether they should hire an individual agent or a real estate team. Here is how the two differ.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why You Can Still Sell Quickly and for Top Dollar in Our Spring Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-you-can-still-sell-quickly-and-for-top-dollar-in-our-spring-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 10:14:53 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you’re looking to sell your home, it’s not too late to hit the spring market.

The reason why it’s important for sellers to hit the spring market is the schools. Many schools in our area start earlier and earlier, typically around mid-August, and these schools won’t accept a housing contract that’s contingent. They’re willing to accept a contract that’s closed, though, so your home has to close before the new homeowners can register in the school system.

Typically, if your buyer is coming from Chicago, they want to be in their home and know where they’re kids are going to school, which means you’re looking at a closing date of late July or mid-August. Remember, it usually takes 30 to 45 days from the time your home is listed to when it’s under contract, and that’s only if it’s priced correctly. From contract to closing, it usually takes another 30 to 45 days.

So, what steps do you need to take to put your home on the market right now?

First, call your Realtor. Get them in your house as soon as possible. They know what the market’s doing and what buyers are looking for. They’ll be your guide to making sure you sell your house quickly. You don’t need to clean or straighten up first—just call them and have them come over as soon as possible.

Your Realtor will be able to tell you exactly what needs to be done in your house. Most of the time, paint goes a long way, but don’t make any upgrades or do any remodeling until you talk to your Realtor and they can tell you what to do to get the most money and help you sell in the quickest time.

“It’s not too late to hit the spring market.”

Also, sign with your Realtor today and get your house listed in the private network. The private network is a behind-the-scenes MLS feature that all agents have access to that allows us to know what’s going on in the market. That way, if someone’s dying to see a house, they can reach out to us Realtors and ask, and it’s up to you when you want to let them in.

The second step is to get your vendors ready. Call whoever you need to help you with the house and get on their calendar. Be aware that they need time to work on your house.

Third, line up your real estate attorney. It’s important that you know who you will use moving forward, and remember—it has to be a real estate attorney. Real estate attorneys will know the ins and outs of these contracts as they come through.

Lastly, figure out where you’re going to go. What if I brought you a contract in 30 days and you still didn’t know where you were going to go? Just listing the house alone can be stressful, but not knowing where you’re going to go is even worse. Make sure you have a plan, and don’t just fold the extra linen in your closet—pack that stuff up and get it out of the way. Start packing other things as well, and make sure you’re mentally committed to the fact that your Realtor is bringing you a contract.

Remember, if your home is not on the market during the spring, that’s okay. Houses sell all year-round, but this is the time when the most buyers are out looking. If you list your home at another time of year, but the process might take longer.

If you’d like to put your home on the market before spring passes, give me a call and I’d be happy to help you get started. If you have any other questions, feel free to reach out to me as well. I’d be happy to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Think the hot spring market has passed you by as a seller? Not so fast—you still have time to list. Here are the steps you need to take.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Think the hot spring market has passed you by as a seller? Not so fast—you still have time to list. Here are the steps you need to take.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Let the Home Inspection Get Out of Control</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-let-the-home-inspection-get-out-of-control.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 10:05:45 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

How do home inspections get out of control? I’ll examine this question from both the buyer’s and seller’s perspective.

First, an inspection is done after a contract has been accepted and agreed upon by both parties. The inspection usually occurs within the first five to seven business days. The inspection is there to see if there are any major issues with the house.

This is where a lot of people get hung up. A major issue would be something like water in the basement, a leaky roof, or mold in the attic. Major issues do not include things like a drawer that doesn’t shut. If a handyman can fix it, it’s probably not a major issue. Keep that in mind when you are negotiating inspection items.

When a buyer signs a contract, the contract states:

“Buyer agrees that minor repairs and routine maintenance items of the real estate do not constitute defects and are not a part of this contingency. The fact that a functioning major component may be at the end of its useful life shall not render such component defective for the purposes of this paragraph.”

If you’ve signed this contract before, you might not have noticed that bolded section. Basically, that means if the property has a 20-year old furnace, you cannot ask for a new furnace. If the roof is at the end of its life but not leaking, you cannot ask for a new roof. It’s really important that you keep that in mind. You’ll want to know how old the mechanicals are when you write the offer.

If you’re a seller and you know that your roof is at the end of its life, you may want to be proactive and get some estimates. That way, you’ll know what the cost might actually be if you were to replace the roof.

Sometimes the buyer comes back with a laundry list of items that they want repaired. That list can turn a $500,000 deal into a disaster, and they may even end up canceling the deal because both parties get upset.

“If you are a buyer, you should only ask for major repair items, not a laundry list of small repairs.”

So, how can you prevent these issues from happening?

First, make sure you hire a real estate attorney. Not a corporate attorney or other kind of attorney—a real estate attorney. They are most familiar with the contracts that real estate agents use.

Next, have your expectations set by your Realtor. If you are the seller, make sure that everything is already out there. Notify the buyers that the roof is old before they write their offer. You don’t want them to be surprised by the inspection. If they know that the roof is 20 years old and they’ll have to spend $10,000 to replace it in the next two years, that can really affect their purchase price or even their ability to buy the home.

You also need to look at the big picture. Are you ready to get this deal done? Is it important for you to secure this deal and not have to go back on the market? If you go back on the market after an inspection, you will have to disclose those items, which can make it more difficult to sell. It’s probably best to try and work with the buyer or seller to finish the deal.

If you are buying or selling a home, it’s really important for you to think about the inspection beforehand. Talk it out with your Realtor and figure out what to expect. If you are a buyer, don’t ask for a laundry list of repairs. Pick the main safety or health issues; those are the most important. If you are a seller, it’s important to realize that you can say no to what the buyer asks for. This is just another negotiation to work through.

If you have any other questions about buying or selling a home, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If a home inspection gets out of control, it can derail your entire real estate deal. I’ll explain how to avoid this today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If a home inspection gets out of control, it can derail your entire real estate deal. I’ll explain how to avoid this today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Properly Price Your Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-properly-price-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 09:59:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you’re planning on selling your home, you need to know how to price it correctly for the market.

Of course, you can use an automated valuation program like Zillow or on an agent’s website. Those work by pulling the data from the homes that have sold in the area. These automated valuations are hit and miss, however. It can be a good place to start.

If you’re planning on selling now, how do you know where your home sits in terms of value? First, let’s talk about the importance of pricing your home.

Pricing is the No. 1 most important thing when it comes to selling your house. There are a few misconceptions that people have when it comes to that.

When it comes to selling, your home is NOT worth:


  What you paid for it
  What your neighbor says
  What you need
  What Zillow says
  What you want
  What it costs to rebuild today


The price of your home is actually what a buyer is willing to pay for it right now in this market.

More people come to view your home within the first three weeks of having it on the market. Those buyers who come in the first three weeks are looking with an agent, and ready to buy so you want your house to be priced correctly. After that, you’re riding the market down. Fewer people will come in after those three weeks if you’re not pricing it correctly. If you price it to high, they’ll move on to another house completely or wait for your price to come down.

“Even if the appraiser values your home at $500,000, if the market isn’t there, it might not actually sell for that much.”

Keep in mind, you can’t price it too low, either. You’ll receive multiple offers that will push the price above your list value.

When it comes to finding the correct price, there are actually two values that I look at: appraised value and market value.

The appraised value is what you see on your computer or on paper. How many bedrooms do you have? What’s your square footage? How many bathrooms do you have? What year was it built? The answers to these questions will determine an appraiser’s valuation.

The market value is determined by the state of the current market. Even if the appraiser values your home at $500,000, if the market isn’t there, it might not actually sell for that much.

This is why you need to be talking to a real estate professional early on in the process, to make sure that the appraised value and the market value match up.

When you’re trying to figure out what the value of your home is, look first at:


  Location. Are you near a school district? Compare your house only to those that are in your immediate area.
  Square footage. Is it the same as a house down the street? There are some tricks that people will use to increase the square footage, so you need to be aware of what the assessor says your square footage is. Remember that the assessment of your square footage is only going to include your first and second floors, not your basement.
  Condition. Make sure that the condition of your home matches the homes in your area. By ‘condition’, I mean something that’s been redone with the last five years.
  Comparables. You can only go off of what has sold in your area and not off of the active homes currently for sale. This is not a good comparable because you haven’t seen that a buyer is willing to pay that list price.


If you’re like to verify where your home is at in terms of value, feel free to reach out to me. I’d love to help you out.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When it comes to selling your home, your price is the most important factor to consider. But how do you properly price a home?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When it comes to selling your home, your price is the most important factor to consider. But how do you properly price a home?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Qualities Should You Expect From Your Agent?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-qualities-should-you-expect-from-your-agent.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 09:51:34 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

What should you expect when working with a real estate agent?

A lot of people can say they’re an agent and can help you buy or sell a house, but it’s important that you get a good feel for your agent because there’s a lot of money at stake when working with them. There are certain qualities you must look for in your agent.

The first and most important quality is honesty, whether it’s good news or bad news. As someone who cares about her clients, I know what it’s like be in difficult situations and have to address topics where there might be some disagreement, like the home’s price or condition. You really have to work with your agent and find out if they’re being truthful with you.

In the past, I’ve done market evaluations on specific homes with other agents who preferred to price those homes $100,000 higher than me. That’s exactly the kind of thing a seller wants to hear, but what happens if you go with that price and, six months later, you’re back at the price the honest agent had said?

“The most important quality is honesty, whether it’s good news or bad news.”

Next, you need to make sure your agent has experience with multiple transactions. I’ve done hundreds of deals, and with each one, I learn something new. However, I also want to foresee problems before they occur, so ask your agent how many transactions they’ve done. Of course, there are many good agents who don’t have a lot of experience, but that’s something you should know about early on.

Also, you need to know whether your agent is a team player. Do they want your house to sell quickly and for top dollar as much as you? Are they fully committed and doing the things they say they’re going to do?

Speaking of teamwork, you need to know if your agent is working by themselves or has a team behind them. In this industry, there’s a lot of things we have to do to list and sell a house. Does your agent have their own support system, and are they communicating with you and accessible? Communication is an important part of your overall teamwork.

Lastly, your agent needs to understand the market. I don’t mean just knowing the comparables that sold across the street or what the appraised value of the home is. I mean whether they truly understand what the market is doing. If they’re experienced and they’re working with a lot of transactions, they can feel what the market is doing.

I have three buyer’s agents on our team, so I know what buyers are saying and what they’re doing. It’s easy for an agent to say the market is trending upward or downward, but what matters is whether they understand the flow and feel of the market.

If you have any questions about what you should require of your agent or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home in our market, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are several important qualities you should expect of a good agent when it comes to selling your home. If they don’t have these qualities, they might not be right for you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are several important qualities you should expect of a good agent when it comes to selling your home. If they don’t have these qualities, they might not be right for you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Do Clients Love Working With the Spaniak Team?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-do-clients-love-working-with-the-spaniak-team.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 09:38:28 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Why should you work with the Spaniak Team to meet your real estate goals? Don’t take it from me—let my satisfied clients do the talking.

John Demakis, one such client, had this to say:

“My wife and I chose the Spaniak Team because we saw the name posted all over the North Shore, and we felt that there was a certain level of credibility to Kati and her team. We saw it in the newspaper, we saw it in people’s yards as they were selling their homes. So we said, ‘When the time is right, I’m going to call Kati.’ She did a great job—very accessible. She runs a big business and she has a huge team, but it’s not so big that you lose touch with her.”

Here at the Spaniak Team, we have a team of buyers’ agents and a showing assistant. If you are looking and your buyer’s agent can’t go out and show you a house, our other agents can. We are very focused on making sure we serve your schedule and not ours.

What makes us truly different is our ability to understand our clients.

“What makes us truly different is our ability to understand our clients.”

“That was one of the things we appreciated the most about Kati,” John says. “She took the time to really talk to us about not only price point, but also what was important to us. She understands the North Shore.”

“There would be houses that would come up, and we would call her and say, ‘Hey, what do you think about this?’ And she would just say, ‘You don’t want to live there. I know what you want, and that’s not it. Let’s find something else.’ There’s a lot of credibility to someone who will tell you no.”

“There’s a level of expertise that she brings to understanding what our needs were. Ultimately, when the house that was right for us came up, she dropped everything. It was on the market for one day. We went and saw it together and she told us it was exactly what we should buy. It was an amazing process for us.”

If you’re looking to buy or sell your home, we encourage you to reach out and contact us by either phone or email. You can also visit our website at www.SpaniakTeam.com. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our team prides itself on our ability to connect with our clients to find out what they really need. Just listen to this happy client’s story about his experience with the Spaniak Team.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our team prides itself on our ability to connect with our clients to find out what they really need. Just listen to this happy client’s story about his experience with the Spaniak Team.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2017 Year-End North Shore Market Update</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017-year-end-north-shore-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 09:30:54 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I want to take a look at the North Shore real estate market and how it has changed recently. When I say North Shore, I’m talking about the area from north of Chicago, beginning in Evanston up until Lake Bluff, from Deerfield, Northbrook and Glenview to the west, and then east to the lake.

The average purchase price in the North Shore for homes is only down by about $10,000 compared to last year. A drop from $677,000 to $668,000 isn’t much of a drop at all. It’s pretty flat.

Here’s an interesting piece of news. There are 400 more homes under contract right now than there were at this time last year. At the same time, there are only 100 more homes listed now than there were at this time last year. This shows us that the market is still vibrant.

“Over 400 more homes under contract right now than there were at this time last year!”

The average time on market is up from 91 days to 118 days, so keep that in mind if you’re thinking of selling anytime soon. Your home will probably be on the market for 30 to 60 days and under contract for another 30 to 60 days prior to closing. You’ll need approximately four months to complete your sale, so it’s time to get ready now if you’re thinking of getting on the market anytime in the spring or summer.

If you want more information about the market on the North Shore follow this link. You can find out home prices, average time on the market, how many homes are under contract and how many houses have closed, among other useful information.

Our schedule is getting filled up. If you’re interested in buying or selling a home or know someone who is, give us a call or send us an email today and we’d be happy to help. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Check out this link to get up to date information about what’s going on in the North Shore real estate market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Check out this link to get up to date information about what’s going on in the North Shore real estate market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Spring Market Starts Before the Super Bowl</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-spring-market-starts-before-the-super-bowl.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 09:24:55 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

You may have heard that the best time to list your home is right after the Super Bowl. It makes sense, because that’s typically the signal of the start of the spring market. However, now it seems that everyone is privy to that information. Therefore, we’re anticipating a big spike in inventory right after the the big game. That increased inventory means more competition for you as a seller.

After that spike in inventory, we tend to see a lot of price reductions. These typically happen in mid to late summer when sellers and buyers alike become desperate. That’s why I think you should get a head start on the market. If you list sooner, you have a better chance to test the market. I also think it gives you a much better chance at receiving a higher price.

“I receive offers every day.”

Even with the weather being cold outside, there are many people wondering when all the new inventory is going to come on the market. People are looking at homes now. I receive offers every day, no matter what time of year it is.

If you’re one of the few houses that’s on the market in the next few months and priced correctly, you could receive multiple offers and be in a great position to sell before the spring market even starts.

If you’re thinking about listing your home in the spring, call me now. I can help you get your home ready to beat the market. I would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The spring market starts earlier than you think. Before the Super Bowl, even.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The spring market starts earlier than you think. Before the Super Bowl, even.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Process Millennials Take to Find Their Desired Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-process-millennials-take-to-find-their-desired-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 09:07:03 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Millennial homebuyers have a different way of searching for homes than previous generations in terms of what they’re looking for and what’s important for them. As a home seller, how should you market to this segment of buyers?

The first thing you have to know is millennials are online a lot, so your home needs to have an online presence and its listing photos have to be outstanding.

Many young millennial buyers are dual-income buyers, and if they’re married, they may have small children in their family too, which means they’re very busy and typically not engaging agents early on in the home buying process. Because of this, open houses have become a more popular option for them and something you should consider.

Many millennials rent from month to month before they buy their home, so they’re in no hurry to locate the best one they can find for the right price, and a lot of them aren’t willing to sacrifice much either. This is why your home needs to be staged and look great in pictures to bolster its online presence.

“Discuss the online marketing strategy for your home with your agent.”

Because most millennials start their home search online, talk to your agent about possible online marketing strategies. By “online,” I mean your agent’s website, their brokerage’s website, and sites like Zillow.

Another important platform for home advertisements is Facebook. Is your agent doing sponsored ads? Are they boosting their posts? Are they doing videos about your house?

Don’t just focus on what the agent’s brokerage is doing for your house—focus on what the agent themselves is doing. They’re the one who is local and can network digitally on your behalf. Our team has a strong internet presence for all of our home seller clients.

If you have any more questions about how to market your home to millennial homebuyers or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home along the Chicago North Shore area, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you want to market your home to millennial homebuyers, it needs to have a strong online presence. That presence starts with your agent.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you want to market your home to millennial homebuyers, it needs to have a strong online presence. That presence starts with your agent.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Effect of Illinois’ Property Tax Increase</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-effect-of-illinois-property-tax-increase.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Kati Spaniak</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-20 09:03:05 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today we’re going to be talking about the Illinois real estate market. More specifically, what I want to talk about is what’s going on with the taxes in Illinois.

Property taxes in Illinois, as most people already know, have completely skyrocketed. I’d say I talk at least once a day with someone who’s asking me about the property taxes and what will happen in the market next year.

Because so many people are talking about it, I have a feeling that we’re heading into a shift in the Illinois market, specifically in Cook and Lake County.

Since taxes have gone up so much, people really cannot afford their homes anymore.

For example, I was at a house two months ago that was worth $260,000, and when they bought it 15 years ago, the taxes were $3,000. Now, those taxes are over $10,000. The owners are struggling to figure out how they’re going to afford their home. And when everyone puts their homes on the market, the tax increase will cause the property values to go down.

“I have a feeling that we’re heading into a shift in the Illinois market.”

I do think that by this time next year, a lot of people are going to be putting their homes up for sale so they can move out of Illinois. Property values have gone down and will likely continue to do so, until the government in Illinois actually understands the ramifications of raising the taxes above the point where many can afford them. It’s a very serious situation for older families and people who are on a fixed income.

The state of Illinois really needs to decide how they’re going to fix the tax crisis because if this isn’t fixed, people will continue to leave the state.

The bottom line is that if you’re considering selling your home in the next couple years, you really want to consider the inventory that’s going to be coming on the market. Make sure you’re pricing your house right, that it looks good, and that your house is properly marketed to buyers.

If you’re looking to buy or sell a home, you can give me a call at 847-379-8813 or email me at Info@SpaniakTeam.com. Have a great day!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Illinois’ property taxes have skyrocketed. What does that mean for the market?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Kati Spaniak</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Illinois’ property taxes have skyrocketed. What does that mean for the market?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Chicago, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Kati Spaniak</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Kati Spaniak</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Spaniak Team - your professional Chicago Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
